An Inventory of the Richard B. Foster papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Stanford Research Institute and SRI International reports, 1960-1986
  - American view of economic relations with the USSR, 1974 (Box-folder 76: 8)
  - Soviet economic performance, 1974 (Box-folder 76: 9)
  - Public-private policy issues, 1976 (Box-folder 76: 10)
  - Nixon doctrine, 1973 (Box-folder 76: 11)
  - Implications of the Nixon doctrine, 1973 (Box-folder 76: 12)
  - Emerging U.S. global strategy, 1973 (Box-folder 76: 13)
  - Role of U.S.-Soviet trade, 1976 (Box-folder 76: 14)
  - Soviet economic problems and technological opportunities, 1979 (Box-folder 76: 15)
  - Limited mobilization, 1980 (Box-folder 76: 16)
  - Education and employment of scientists and engineers, 1981 (Box-folder 76: 17)
  - Regulatory impacts on national security telecommunications, 1981 (Box-folder 76: 18)
  - Framework for national communications system, 1982 (Box-folder 77: 1)
  - The science race, 1981 (Box-folder 77: 2)
  - Forecastability of national security telecommunications requirements, 1981 (Box-folder 77: 3)
  - Dialectics of U.S. domestic and foreign policies, 1980 (Box-folder 77: 4)
  - A long range strategic overview, 1975 (Box-folder 77: 5)
  - From assured destruction to assured survival, 1980 (Box-folder 77: 6)
  - National goals and survival measures, 1980 (Box-folder 77: 7)
  - An approach to determination of strategic command control communication requirements, 1963 (Box-folder 77: 8)
  - Impact of ballistic missile defense on arms control prospects, 1966 (Box-folder 77: 9)
  - Criteria for political acceptability of arms control and disarmament concept, 1964 (Box-folder 77: 10)
  - Evaluation of systems of fire development, 1970 (Box-folder 77: 11)
  - Exploratory analysis of fire storms, 1965 (Box-folder 77: 12)
  - Postattack recovery of damaged urban areas, 1966 (Box-folder 77: 13)
  - A system of centers for research into counter-guerrilla operations, 1961 (Box-folder 77: 14)
  - Conduct of U.S. foreign economic relations, 1977 (Box-folder 78: 1)
  - World political and economic trends in the 1980s, 1981 (Box-folder 78: 2-4)
  - Overall balance of power in the 1970s, 1971 (Box-folder 78: 5)
  - Synthesis of political, economic and strategic factors in Southeast Asia, 1977 (Box-folder 78: 6)
  - Four most critical items requiring resources, 1980 (Box-folder 78: 7)
  - Army intelligence systems analysis study, 1966 (Box-folder 78: 8)
  - Joint public/private policy development on national issues, 1981 (Box-folder 78: 8)
  - Global strategic balance and regional security issues, 1979 (Box-folder 78: 9)
  - Strategic planning agenda, 1981 (Box-folder 78: 10)
  - Study of controlled conflict, 1975 (Box-folder 79: 1)
  - National strategy in a decade of change, 1972 (Box-folder 79: 2-3)
  - National policy and realism, 1975 (Box-folder 79: 4)
  - Prolonged war in Soviet strategy, 1981 (Box-folder 79: 5)
  - Observations on Soviet defense expenditures, 1975 (Box-folder 79: 6)
  - Report on visit to Japan and Korea, 1977 (Box-folder 79: 7)
  - A proposed concept for government-business cooperation, 1975 (Box-folder 79: 8)
  - Force relationships and interactions, 1970 (Box-folder 79: 9)
- Speeches and writings, 1955-1989
  - With Francis P. Hoeber,"Cost-Effectiveness Analysis for Strategic Decisions", 1955 (Box-folder 80: 1)
  - "Values, Power, and Strategy", 1959 (Box-folder 80: 2)
  - "The Impact of Ballistic Missile Defense on Arms Control Prospects", 1966 (Box-folder 80: 3)
  - "Points for Consideration in Debating the Ballistic Missile Issue", 1969 (Box-folder 80: 4)
  - "Strategic Interactions: Offensive-Defensive Systems and Strategic Arms Limitations", 1969 (Box-folder 80: 5)
  - "The Nixon Doctrine: An Emerging U.S. Policy", 1973 (Box-folder 80: 6)
  - "The Meaning of Non-Convergence", 1974 (Box-folder 80: 7)
  - Speech to SRI Board, 1974 (Box-folder 80: 8)
  - Speech to Business Council, 1974 (Box-folder 80: 9)
  - Article on crisis of American society, 1975 (Box-folder 80: 10)
  - Interview with Richard B. Foster, 1975 (Box-folder 80: 11)
  - "Challenges of the 1980s: An American's Perception", 1977 (Box-folder 80: 12)
  - "Long Range Projections of the Global Strategic Environment", 1977 (Box-folder 80: 13)
  - "An American's View of International Issues", 1978 (Box-folder 80: 14)
  - "Soviet Economic Performance as Reflecting State Goals and Objectives", 1978 (Box-folder 80: 15)
  - "The Substance of Comparative Strategy", 1978 (Box-folder 80: 16)
  - With Francis P. Hoeber,"Ideology and Economic Analysis: The Case of Soviet Civil Defense", 1979 (Box-folder 81: 1)
  - "From Assured Destruction to Assured Survival", 1980 (Box-folder 81: 2)
  - "Group Chairman's Closing Remarks", 1980 (Box-folder 81: 3)
  - With Francis P. Hoeber,"Limited Mobilization: A Strategy for Preparedness in the Eighties", 1980 (Box-folder 81: 4)
  - "A Preventive Strategy for the Middle East", 1980 (Box-folder 81: 5)
  - "Protection of the Individual and His Rights in Theater Nuclear Warfare", 1980 (Box-folder 81: 6)
  - "The Status of and Prospect for the New Cold War", 1980 (Box-folder 81: 7)
  - "Soviet Concepts of Victory and Prolonged War", 1981 (Box-folder 81: 8)
  - "Regulatory Impacts on National Security", 1981 (Box-folder 81: 9)
  - With William M. Carpenter,"Great Power Interactions in Northeast Asia", 1982 (Box-folder 81: 10)
  - "On Prolonged Nuclear War", 1982 (Box-folder 81: 11)
  - "In Memoriam Herman Kahn", 1983 (Box-folder 81: 12)
  - With William M. Carpenter,"The Strategic Triangle: Who's Playing Whose Card?", 1983 (Box-folder 81: 13)
  - "Imperatives for a Bipartisan Foreign Policy Process for the Future", 1984 (Box-folder 81: 14)
  - Introduction to Japanese edition of writings, 1984 (Box-folder 81: 15)
  - "Naval Power in National Grand Strategy", 1984 (Box-folder 81: 16)
  - "Soviet Competition", 1984 (Box-folder 81: 17)
  - "Comments on Paper by Roger E. Kanet and Daniel R. Kempton", 1985 (Box-folder 82: 1)
  - Interview with Richard B. Foster, 1985 (Box-folder 82: 2)
  - "Necessity for Strategic Defense: Opposition and Prospects", 1986 (Box-folder 82: 3)
  - "SDI and Soviet Goals", 1986 (Box-folder 82: 4)
  - "Die Bundesrepublik Deutschland in der NATO", 1987 (Box-folder 82: 4)
  - With William M. Carpenter,"The Strategic Importance of the Greater Pacific Basin", 1987 (Box-folder 82: 6)
  - "Strategy in Perspective", 1987 (Box-folder 82: 7)
  - "Notes on Trip to the PRC (People's Republic of China)", 1988 (Box-folder 82: 8)
  - Reply to letter to the editor, 1988 (Box-folder 82: 9)
  - "Strategic Dimensions of the Drug War", 1988 (Box-folder 82: 10)
  - "Strategy for a Drug War", 1988 (Box-folder 82: 11)
  - "Dangers in NATO Pact Arms Control Negotiations", 1989 (Box-folder 82: 12)
- Correspondence and memoranda, 1955-1979
  - 1955-1961 (Box-folder 82: 13)
  - 1964 (Box-folder 82: 14)
  - 1965 (Box-folder 82: 15)
  - 1966 (Box-folder 82: 16-17)
  - 1967 (Box-folder 82: 18)
  - 1970 (Box-folder 82: 19)
  - 1971 (Box-folder 82: 20)
  - 1972 (Box-folder 83: 1)
  - 1973 (Box-folder 83: 2)
  - 1974 (Box-folder 83: 3-5)
  - 1975 (Box-folder 83: 6-7)
  - 1976 (Box-folder 83: 8)
  - 1977 (Box-folder 83: 9)
  - 1978 (Box-folder 83: 10)
  - 1979 (Box-folder 83: 11)
- Printed matter, 1964-1999
  - Bulletins and newsletters, 1989-1999
    - 1989-1991 (Box-folder 84: 1)
    - 1992-1995 (Box-folder 84: 2)
    - 1998 (Box-folder 84: 3)
    - 1999 (Box-folder 84: 4)
  - Monographs, 1976-1989
    - 1976 (Box-folder 84: 5)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 84: 6)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 84: 7-8)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 84: 9)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 85: 1)
  - Reports, 1964-1998
    - 1964 (Box-folder 85: 2)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 85: 3)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 85: 4)
    - 1973 (Box-folder 85: 5)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 86: 1)
    - 1978-1979 (Box-folder 86: 2)
    - 1982-1983 (Box-folder 86: 3)
    - 1984-1986 (Box-folder 86: 4)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 86: 5-6)
    - 1990-1998 (Box-folder 86: 7)
  - Serial issues, 1966-1986
    - 1966 (Box-folder 86: 8)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 86: 9)
- Overhead transparencies used in SRI presentations, 1970-1976
  - American national security issues, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 87: 1-22)
  - Military policy of the Soviet Union, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 87: 23-40)
  - NATO defense policy, 1970 (Box-folder 87: 41-48)
  - Strategic Studies Center projects, 1971 (Box-folder 87: 49-50)